jackssmallengines.com 2019-04-11

# Privacy Policy - Jacks Small Engines

## JACKS SMALL ENGINE & GENERATOR SERVICE, LLC

Jacks Small Engine & Generator Service, LLC and family of websites respects the privacy of all individuals that visit our websites. The purpose of this Privacy policy is to provide you with information about how we collect, use, and share the information we collect from our visitors. Jacks Small Engines & Generator Service, LLC from time to time may change our privacy policies and will update those changes at this webpage location. Your continued use of our website indicates your acceptance of such changes. 

## The Types of Personal Information We Collect:

We collect certain personal information about visitors and users of our Sites.

The most common types of information we collect include things like: usernames, member names, email addresses, IP addresses, other contact details, blogs, payment information such as payment agent details, transactional details, tax information, support queries, forum comments, content you direct us to make available on our Sites (such as item descriptions) and web analytics data. We will also collect personal information from job applications (such as, your resume, the application form itself, cover letter and interview notes). 

## How we collect personal information:

We collect personal information directly when you provide it to us, automatically as you navigate through the Sites, or through other people when you use services associated with the Sites. 

We collect your personal information when you provide it to us when you complete membership registration and buy or provide items or services on our Sites, subscribe to a newsletter, email list, submit feedback, enter a contest, fill out a survey, use our forum, comment on blogs, or send us a communication. 

## Personal information we collect about you from others:

Although we generally collect personal information directly from you, on occasion, we also collect certain categories of personal information about you from other sources. In particular: 

  * financial and/or transaction details from payment providers located in the US and worldwide;
  * third party service providers (like Google, Facebook), which may provide information about you when you link, connect, or login to your account with the third party provider and they send us information such as your registration and profile from that service. The information varies and is controlled by that service provider or as authorized by you via your privacy settings at that service provider; and 
  * other third party sources/ and or partners, whereby we receive additional information about you (to the extent permitted by applicable law), such as demographic data or fraud detection information, and combine it with information we have about you. For example, fraud warnings from service providers like identity verification service. 

## How we use personal information:

  * operating the sites;
  * providing you with services described on the Sites;
  * verifying your identity when you sign in to any of our Sites;
  * responding to support tickets, and helping facilitate the resolution of any disputes;
  * updating you with operational news and information about our Sites and services e.g. to notify you about changes to our Sites, website disruptions or security updates;
  * carrying out technical analysis to determine how to improve the Sites and services we provide;
  * monitoring activity on the Sites, e.g. to identify potential fraudulent activity and to ensure compliance with the user terms that apply to the Sites;
  * managing our relationship with you, e.g. by responding to your comments or queries submitted to us on the Sites or asking for your feedback or whether you want to participate in a survey;
  * managing our legal and operational affairs (including, managing risks relating to content and fraud matters);
  * improving our products and services.
  * providing general administrative and performance functions and activities; and
  * processing your job application to Jacks Small Engines.

Where you give us consent:

  * providing you with marketing information about products and services which we feel may interest you; and
  * customising our services and websites, like advertising that appear on the Site – where this involves the use of cookies or similar technologies – in order to provide a more personalised experience.
  * For purposes which are required by law.
  * For the purpose of responding to requests by government, a court of law, or law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation.

## Opt Out - Marketing Choices regarding your personal information:

Jacks Small Engine & Generator Service, LLC may send you communications regarding its services. Jacks Small Engine & Generator Service, LLC provides you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such communications by indicating your desire to opt-out. If you would like to opt out of receiving communications from us please use our [Contact Page](https://www.jackssmallengines.com/contact-us.aspx).

To unsubscribe from The Jacks Small Engines Newsletter Email list: [Unsubscribe Here](http://jackssmallengines.us5.list-manage.com/unsubscribe?u=74b8acd1012ab13b7dd17ecc5&id=b9c41b695b). 

Even if you opt out of receiving marketing messages, we may still contact you for transactional purposes like confirming or following up on an order or service request, asking you to review a product or service you have ordered, or notifying you of product recalls.

You also have choices about cookies, as described below. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject cookies some parts of our Sites may not work properly in your case.

## Cookies and web analytics:

When you visit our sites, there’s certain information that’s recorded which is generally anonymous information and does not reveal your identity. If you’re logged into your account some of this information could be associated with your account. We’re talking about the following kinds of details:

  * your IP address or proxy server IP address’;
  * the domain name you requested;
  * the name of your internet service provider is sometimes captured depending on the configuration of your ISP connection;
  * the date and time of your visit to the website;
  * the length of your session;
  * the pages which you have accessed;
  * the number of times you access our site within any month;
  * the file URL you look at and information relating to it;
  * the website which referred you to our Sites; and
  * the operating system which your computer uses.

_We will not give or sell your individual information to any outside company for its use in marketing or solicitation._

Occasionally, we will use third party advertising companies to serve ads based on prior visits to our Sites. For example, if you visit our Sites, you may later see an add for our products and services when you visit a different Site. Read more about your options in our cookie policy.

## Internet-Based Ads

Data about your online activities is being collected for use in targeted advertising tailored to your individual interests. Interest-based ads may be displayed to you based on your activities interacting with our website, such as making a purchase, viewing products, or other informational content. We use internet advertising vendors to provide you with relevant and useful ads. These ads appear on other websites that are compliant with internet advertising policies.

You can choose to have your information collected for that purpose, or opt out. To opt out of having your online behavior collected for advertising purposes, visit the Network Advertising Initiative, or [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

OR

Opt out by clicking the Ad Choices Icon     located at the top corner of the ad. Then you may choose to opt out, disable, or change your ad settings. 

## Security

When you place orders on our websites, all of your order information, including your credit card number and delivery address, is transmitted through the Internet using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. SSL technology causes your browser to encrypt your order information before transmitting it to our secure server. SSL technology, an industry standard, is designed to prevent someone other than operators of our websites from capturing and viewing your personal information.

While we use industry standard means to protect our websites and your information, the Internet is not 100% secure. The measures we use are appropriate for the type of information we collect. We cannot promise that your use of our websites or mobile applications will be completely safe. We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. Online access to your personal information is protected with a password you select. We strongly recommend that you do not share your password. 

## Information about children:

Our Sites are not suitable for children under the age of 18 years, so if you are under 18 we ask that you do not use our Sites or give us your personal information. If you are under 18 years old, you can browse the Sites but you’ll need the supervision of a parent or guardian to become a registered user. It’s the responsibility of parents or guardians to monitor their children’s use of our Sites.

## Information you make public or give to others:

If you make your personal information available to other people, we can’t control or accept responsibility for the way they will use or manage that data. There are lots of ways that you can find yourself providing information to other people, like when you post a public message on a forum thread, share information via social media, or make contact with another user (such as a third party Author) whether via our Sites or directly via email. Before making your information publicly available or giving your information to anyone else, think carefully. If giving information to another user via our Sites, ask them how they will handle your information. If you’re sharing information via another website, check the privacy policy for that site to understand its information management practices as this privacy policy will not apply.

## How long we keep your personal information:

We retain your personal information for as long as is necessary to provide the services to you and others, and to comply with our legal obligations. Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information we will retain information from deleted accounts as necessary for our legitimate business interests, to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the terms of service and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## When we need to update this policy:

We will need to change this policy from time to time in order to make sure it stays up to date with the latest legal requirements and any changes to our privacy management practices. When we do change the policy, we’ll make sure to notify you about such changes, where required. A copy of the latest version of this policy will always be available on this page.

We’re really glad you made it to the end of the privacy policy, because knowing this stuff is the best way to understand how your personal information is used and how to best manage it! 

If you’re a user or visitor in the European Economic Area these rights also apply to you:

For the purposes of applicable EU data protection law (including the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), we are a ‘data controller’ of your personal information.

## How you can access your personal information:

You are also entitled to ask us to port your personal information (i.e. to transfer in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, to you), to erase it, or restrict its processing. You also have rights to object to some processing that is based on our legitimate interests, such as profiling that we perform for the purposes of direct marketing, and, where we have asked for your consent to process your data, to withdraw this consent as more fully described below.

These rights are limited in some situations – for example, we can demonstrate that we have a legal requirement to process your personal information. In some instances, this means that we may retain some data even if you withdraw your consent.

Where we require your personal information to comply with legal or contractual obligations, then provision of such data is mandatory: if such data is not provided, then we will not be able to manage our contractual relationship with you, or to meet obligations placed on us. In all other cases, provision of requested personal information is optional.

## How you can contact us:

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or the way in which we have been managing your personal information, please contact us by submitting the [contact form](http://www.jackssmallengines.com/contact-us.aspx) with your inquiry. Or write to us at:   
Jacks Small Engines  
ATTN: Privacy Policy  
105 Industry Lane  
Forest Hill, MD 21050 

Jacks Small Engine & Generator Service, LLC 2018
